Guide to the Joseph Bruchac Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Joseph Bruchac papers
1959-2006
1980-1998
YCAL MSS 740
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
136.68
(146 boxes) + 1 roll.
The Joseph Bruchac Papers contain correspondence with family, publishers, and storytelling and literary colleagues; drafts of writings, on paper and computer disks; materials concerning writing workshops taught by Bruchac in prisons; writings of others, including Native American authors; and subject files, photographs, audiocassettes, and videocassettes, many relating to storytelling performances at festivals and schools, or to Native American storytelling and literary organizations, including Returning the Gift Native American writers conferences, 1990s, and the Wordcraft Circle of Native Writers & Storytellers, 1990s-2000s. Research strengths include Bruchac's writings and storytelling; teaching of Abenaki and other Native American cultures; 20th-century Native American literature, children's literature, and literary organizations; and 20th-century American small presses.
Bruchac, Joseph, 1942-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Ken Lopez on the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund, Danford N. Barney, Jr. Fund, Sinclair Lewis Fund, Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, and Theatre Guild Fund, 1996-2006.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 84, 99, and 145 (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Joseph Bruchac (1942-)
Joseph Bruchac, Native American storyteller; author of novels, stories, poems, essays, and children's literature; and editor of poetry and fiction anthologies. Bruchac's storytelling and writings draw on his Abenaki ancestry and culture of Native Americans of the northeastern United States. Bruchac has been active in the Wordcraft Circle of Native Writers & Storytellers, and with his wife, publisher and editor Carol Bruchac, founded the Greenfield Review Literary Center and The Greenfield Review Press.
Scope and Contents
The Joseph Bruchac Papers contain correspondence with family, publishers, and storytelling and literary colleagues; drafts of writings, on paper and computer disks; materials concerning writing workshops taught by Bruchac in prisons; writings of others, including Native American authors; and subject files, photographs, audiocassettes, and videocassettes, many relating to storytelling performances at festivals and schools, or to Native American storytelling and literary organizations, including Returning the Gift Native American writers conferences, 1990s, and the Wordcraft Circle of Native Writers & Storytellers, 1990s-2000s. Research strengths include Bruchac's writings and storytelling; teaching of Abenaki and other Native American cultures; 20th-century Native American literature, children's literature, and literary organizations; and 20th-century American small presses.
Arrangement
Organized into seven groupings: November 1996 Acquisition; September 1998 Acquisition; February 1999 Acquisition; April 1999 Acquisition; July 2006 Acquisition; September 2006 Acquisition; and Other Acquisitions.
Abenaki Indians; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Children's literature, American; Indians of North America -- Juvenile literature; Indians of North America -- Northeastern States; Prisoners' writings, American; Small presses -- United States; Storytelling -- United States; Writers' workshops -- United States; Audiovisual materials -- United States -- 20th Century; Audiocassettes -- United States -- 20th Century; Born digital -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographs -- United States -- 20th Century; Videocassettes -- United States -- 20th Century; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Native American literature; Bruchac, Carol; Bruchac, Joseph, 1942-; Wordcraft Circle of Native Writers & Storytellers; North American Native Writers' Festival
- November 1996 Acquisition, 1959-1998; 78.25 linear feet (83 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into four subseries: Correspondence, arranged chronologically, 1966-1995; Writings, arranged alphabetically by publisher, followed by other writings; Subject Files, arranged roughly alphabetically; and Other Papers, arranged roughly chronologically, 1970-1990s.
  Scope and Contents
  Writings include materials relating to books, most published during the 1970s-1990s, and to anthologies, poems, stories, and writing workshops taught by Bruchac in prisons. Additional materials relating to writings are in the Correspondence and Subject Files series. Subject Files also contain subgroups concerning projects completed during the 1990s and to Native American storytelling. Other Papers includes files, photographs, and videocassettes relating Bruchac's writing and storytelling performances.
  - Correspondence, 1966-1995
    - Correspondence, 1966-1969, 1970-1972; 12 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1975; 28 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1978; 33 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1979; 15 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1982; 14 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1984; 21 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1985; 14 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1986; 13 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1986-1987; 13 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, 1987-1988; 12 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1990; 13 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1991; 13 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence, 1991-1992; 13 (Box 13)
    - Correspondence, 1992-1993; 17 (Box 14)
    - Correspondence, 1993-1994; 13 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, 1994-1995; 23 (Box 16)
    - Postage stamps, undated (Box 16)
  - Writings
    - August House, undated; 3 (Box 17)
    - Bear & Company, 1987-1990 (Box 17)
    - Blue Heron, 1995 (Box 17)
    - BOA, 1996 (Box 17)
    - Book Links, 1994 (Box 17)
    - The Chauncy Press, 1987-1989 (Box 17)
    - Children's Press, 1991-1992 (Box 17)
    - Cold Mountain Press
      - The Dreams of Jesse Brown, undated; 5 (Box 17)
      - This Earth is a Drum, 1976 (Box 17)
      - Entering Onondaga, 1976-1977; 2 (Box 17)
      - Flow, 1974-1975; 2 (Box 17)
      - How to Start and Sustain a Literary Magazine, 1979-1981; 4 (Box 18)
    - The Council Press, 1993 (Box 18)
    - Crossing Press
      - Hoop Snakes, 1990-1991 (Box 18)
      - Iroquois Stories, 1981-1996; 4 (Box 18)
      - Native American Sweat Lodge, undated; 3 (Box 18)
      - The Next World, 1977-1978; 2 (Box 18)
      - Return of the Sun, 1989-1994; 2 (Box 19)
    - Dial Books
      - Bowman's Store: a Journey to Myself, 1995-1996; 9 (Box 19)
      - Bowman's Store: a Journey to Myself, 1995-1996; 5 (Box 20)
      - Children of the Longhouse, 1995-1996; 8 (Box 20)
      - Eagle Song, 1995-1996; 2 (Box 20)
      - The First Strawberries, 1992-1995; 2 (Box 21)
      - The Great Ball Game, 1994-1995 (Box 21)
      - The Milky Way, 1993-1994; 2 (Box 21)
      - The One Who Heard the Hymn of Peace: A Story of Hiawatha, undated (Box 21)
      - Pushing up the Sky, 1996 (Box 21)
      - Correspondence with Cindy Kane, 1991-1993 (Box 21)
      - Native American plays, 1996 (Box 21)
    - Fulcrum Publishing
      - "All My Relatives", 1989-1991 (Box 21)
      - Dawn Land, 1993-1995; 8 (Box 21)
      - Dawn Land, 1989-1995; 11 (Box 22)
      - Dog People, 1994-1995; 2 (Box 23)
      - Keepers of the Animals, 1989-1993; 11 (Box 23)
      - Keepers of the Animals, 1989-1993; 3 (Box 24)
      - Keepers of the Earth, 1985, undated; 10 (Box 24)
      - Keepers of the Earth, 1984-1991; 15 (Box 25)
      - Keepers of Life, 1993, undated; 5 (Box 25)
      - Keepers of Life, 1993-1994; 6 (Box 26)
      - Keepers of the Night, 1992-1993; 4 (Box 26)
      - Long River, 1993-1995; 15 (Box 27)
      - Long River, 1995, undated; 2 (Box 28)
      - Native American Gardening, 1994-1996; 8 (Box 28)
      - Roots of Survival, 1996, undated; 3 (Box 28)
      - Roots of Survival, 1996, undated; 3 (Box 29)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 29)
    - Glencoe, 1993 (Box 29)
    - Greenfield Review Press, 1993 (Box 29)
    - Harcourt Brace & Company
      - Between Earth and Sky, 1995-1996; 8 (Box 30)
      - "Seven Generations", 1995-1996; 6 (Box 30)
      - "The Song of the Buffalo", 1996 (Box 30)
      - Telling Tales, 1995-1996; 6 (Box 30)
      - Unidentified, 1993-1996; 2 (Box 30)
    - HarperCollins
      - The Boy Who Lived with the Bears, 1995 (Box 31)
      - Native Wisdom, 1994-1996; 5 (Box 31)
      - Unidentified, undated; 4 (Box 31)
    - New Society Publishers, undated (Box 31)
    - North American Press, 1993-1995; 2 (Box 31)
    - Philomel/Putnam
      - A Boy Called Slow, 1993-1995 (Box 31)
      - "The Buffalo Orphans", undated (Box 31)
      - The Earth Under Sky Bear's Feet, 1993-1995; 2 (Box 31)
      - Fox Song, 1991-1994; 2 (Box 31)
      - "Handprints" and other material, 1992-1996; 4 (Box 31)
      - "Handprints" and other material, 1992-1996; 28 (Box 32)
      - Thirteen Moons on Turtle's Back, 1991-1992; 2 (Box 32)
      - Unidentified, undated; 9 (Box 33)
    - Troll/Bridgewater
      - "ABC Book", 1996; 2 (Box 33)
      - "Animals", 1995 (Box 33)
      - Flying with the Eagle, Racing the Great Bear, 1993-1995; 2 folders (Box 33)
      - Four Ancestors, 1995 (Box 33)
      - The Girl who Married the Moon, 1995 (Box 33)
      - "Thanksgiving Book", 1995 (Box 33)
      - Unidentified, undated; 7 (Box 33)
    - University of Arizona Press
      - Survival This Way: Interviews with Native American Poets, 1985-1987; 14 (Box 34)
      - Survival This Way: Interviews with Native American Poets, 1985-1987; 28 (Box 35)
      - Survival This Way: Interviews with Native American Poets, 1985; 14 (Box 36)
      - Survival This Way: Interviews with Native American Poets (audiocassettes)
        - "Abenaki Stories" told by Joseph Bruchac, undated; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091242645)
          Contents of this audiocassette are listed below.
          Gluskabe Stories
          "The Wind Eagle"
          "The Game Animals"
          "Gluskabe and Dzidzis"
          "Azaban the Raccoon"
          "Gluskabe's Game Bag"
        - Carroll Arnett (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1983 April 6; 1 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002091399817)
        - Carroll Arnett, side 3 (2 of 2 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002091399825)
        - Art Inside, "California Prison Artists", undated; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091242728)
        - Peter Blue Cloud, 1983 February 7; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091242892)
        - Border Crossings, WMHT, undated; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091399999)
        - Breakfast at the Hanover Inn, "Abenaki Indians", 1984 April 6; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091242504)
          Host: Karen Kayen. Guest: Michael Caoute.
        - Joseph Bruchac, CKON, 1985; 1 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002091399882)
        - Joseph Bruchac dialogue, University of Minnesota, 1985 March 6; 1 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002091399874)
        - Joseph Bruchac interview, All Things Considered, NPR, 1981 February; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091242710)
        - Joseph Bruchac, interview at Mankato State, 1985 March 7; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091242512)
        - Joseph Bruchac, New Letters on the Air, University of Missouri, K.C., 1983 March; 1 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002091399866)
        - Joseph Bruchac, The North Country Storytelling Festival, 1984 January 8; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091242702)
        - Joseph Bruchac, Old Songs, 1990 June 24; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091242629)
        - Joseph Bruchac, Pennsylvania Prison Poets, 1985; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091242488)
          Dolby B, running time: 28:05
        - Joseph Bruchac reading, V.C.I., Bristol, VA, undated; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091400003)
        - Joseph Bruchac, storytelling at St. Lawrence, University North County Storytelling Festival, 1984 January 8; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091242553)
        - Joseph Bruchac "Talk Story" interview, KSOR, Ashland, Oregon, 1984 February 6; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091242520)
        - Joseph Bruchac, WFCR "Poems to a Listener", undated; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091242694)
        - Joseph Bruchac, Woodland Pattern Reading, Milwaukee, 1985 March 9; 1 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002091399890)
        - Joseph Bruchac and John Moody, Talk at Vins. (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1984 April 5; 1 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002091399908)
        - Joseph Bruchac and John Moody, Talk at Vins. (2 of 2 audiocassettes), 1984 April 5; 1 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002091399916)
        - Diane Burns, 1985 March 22; 1 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002091399833)
        - Barney Bush, 1984 September 29; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091242751)
        - Barney Bush and Joy Harjo (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1983 January 19; 1 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002091399841)
        - Barney Bush and Joy Harjo (2 of 2 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002091399858)
        - Robert J. Conley, 1984 March 24; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091242686)
        - Elizabeth Cook-Lynn, 1986 April 23; 1 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002091399932)
        - Creative Tracks, WSLU Radio Shows on Native American Arts, 1992 Fall; 1 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002091399924)
        - Charlotte DeClue, 1984 December 8; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091242900)
        - Louise Erdrich, 1986 April 17; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091242785)
        - John and Eva Fadden, 1983 January 7; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091242942)
        - First Person Feminine interview with Judy Ray, fourth series, 1983 December 5; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091242587)
        - Gluskabe Stories, final mixes, undated; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091242611)
        - Paula Gunn Allen, 1983 February 4; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091242876)
        - Joy Harjo, undated; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091242967)
        - Lance Henson, 1984 December 8; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091242652)
        - Geary Hobson, 1982 December 8; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091242850)
        - Linda Hogan, 1983 May 20; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091242868)
        - Alex Jacobs, "Karoniaktatie", 1984 September 20; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091242744)
        - Maurice Kenny (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1983 January 13; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091243007)
        - Maurice Kenny (2 of 2 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091242991)
        - Frank La Pena, Tauhindauli (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1983 February 6; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091242801)
        - Frank La Pena, hand games (2 of 2 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091242819)
        - Harold Littlebird, 1982 December 2; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091242470)
        - N. Scott Momaday, 1982 December 7; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091242835)
        - Victor Montejo reading, 1982 November 15; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091242769)
        - New Letters on the Air, "Native American Indians", undated; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091242579)
        - New Letters on the Air, "Prison Poets", Rolph Dieter Brinkmann, undated; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091242678)
        - Duane Niatum (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1983 December 12; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091242975)
        - Duane Niatum (2 of 2 audiocassettes), 1982 December 12; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091242983)
        - William Oandasan, 1985 February 12; 1 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002091399957)
        - Louis Oliver and Cherokee Gospel Music, 1982 April 30; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091242934)
        - Simon Ortiz, Montana Book (empty case), 1981 November 4 (Box 37)
        - Simon Ortiz, 1982 December 9; 1 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002091399940)
        - Parabola Preview tape, Iroquois Stories told by Joseph Bruchac, 1990 May 22; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091242595)
          Content included on this audiocassette are listed below.
          "Rabbit and Fox"
          "The Boy Who Lived with the Bears"
          "How the Birds got their Feathers"
          "Turtle Makes War on Men"
          "Chipmunk and Bear"
          "Rabbit's Snow Dance"
        - Prison Poetry, Great Atlantic Radio Conspiracy, undated; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091242603)
        - Carter Revard (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1986 April 28; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091242660)
        - Carter Revard (2 of 2 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091242827)
        - Ronald Rogers, 1982 December 8; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091242496)
        - Rokwaho (Danny Thompson), Mohawk Reservation, 1985 September 24; 1 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002091399965)
        - Wendy Rose, 1983 February 2; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091243015)
        - Ralph Salisbury, Eugene, Oregon, 1984 February 8; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091242736)
        - Saratoga Springs Library writing workshop reading, 1982 June 28; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091242546)
        - Leslie Silko (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1982 December 7; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091242918)
        - Leslie Silko (2 of 2 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091242926)
        - Skunny - Wundy's Skipping Stone, studio, 1990 June; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091242561)
        - Mary Tall Mountain, undated; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091242793)
        - UWW / Comstock Discussion (2nd tape), 1974 September 25; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091242637)
        - Gerald Vizenor (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1995 February 9; 1 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002091399973)
        - Gerald Vizenor (2 of 2 audiocassettes), 1985 February 9; 1 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002091399981)
        - Roberta Hill Whiteman, 1984 March 26; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091242959)
        - WSPN interview on prison program, undated; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091242538)
        - Ray Young Bear, 1984 March 24; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091242884)
        - Ofelia Zepeda, 1982 December 5; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091242843)
      - Unidentified, undated; 2 (Box 41)
    - University of Georgia Press, undated (Box 41)
    - Other Writings
      - Anthologies
        Edited or with introduction by Bruchac
        - Harper Anthology of 20th Century Native American Poetry, 1986-1988; 4 (Box 41)
        - I Become Part of It, undated (Box 41)
        - Unidentified, 1988-1995; 2 (Box 41)
      - Other writing projects, undated; 13 (Box 41)
      - Other writing projects, undated; 29 (Box 42)
      - Poems, published
        - Blue Cloud Quarterly. "Remembering the Dawn", 1983 (Box 43)
        - Crosscultural Communications. "Translator's Son", 1977-1984; 2 (Box 43)
        - Ion Books. "Tracking", 1986 (Box 43)
        - Landlocked Press. "Walking With My Sons", 1985 (Box 43)
        - Unicorn Press. "The Good Message of Handsome Lake", 1977-1981; 2 (Box 43)
        - White Pine Press. "Near the Mountains", 1984; 6 (Box 43)
      - Poems, unpublished, 1977-1984; 7 (Box 43)
      - Poems, unpublished, 1978-1987; 20 (Box 44)
      - Poems, drafts, 1987, undated; 3 (Box 44)
      - Poems, drafts, 1972-1986; 19 (Box 45)
      - Poems, drafts, undated; 19 (Box 46)
      - Novels and journals from Ghana
        - Breaks, 1986; 4 (Box 47)
        - Chenoo, 1984; 3 (Box 47)
        - Journals, 1960's-1970's; 5 (Box 47)
        - Journals, 1960's-1970's; 20 (Box 48)
        - Journals, 1960's-1970's; 6 (Box 49)
        - "Shaman Song", 1978-1980; 5 (Box 49)
      - Short Fiction
        - Road to Black Mountain, undated; 2 (Box 49)
        - "Turtle Meat", 1985-1992; 3 (Box 49)
        - Unidentified, 1971-1985; 15 (Box 50)
      - Essays and reviews
        - "Gathering the Bones", 1985; 3 (Box 50)
        - Unidentified, undated; 5 (Box 51)
        - The Broken Rainbow, 1996, undated; 16 (Box 51)
        - The Broken Rainbow, 1994-1996; 4 (Box 52)
      - African writings
        - "The Gaboon Viper", undated (Box 52)
        - No Telephone to Heaven, 1966-1982; 8 (Box 53)
        - No Telephone to Heaven, 1966-1982; 9 (Box 53)
        - Unidentified, undated; 11 (Box 54)
      - Prison writing workshops, 1975-1986; 19 (Box 54)
      - Prison writing workshops, 1975-1986; 18 (Box 55)
      - Student writings, 1962-1975; 17 (Box 56)
      - Student writings, 1965-1977; 21 (Box 57)
  - Subject Files
    - Essay on war, 1959 (Box 58)
    - The American Book Awards: translations, 1982; 2 (Box 58)
    - Anthologies: Joseph Bruchac, 1982 (Box 58)
    - Peter Klappert anthology, 1982 (Box 58)
    - A Gift of Tongues, 1985 (Box 58)
    - Contemporary dramatists, 1974 (Box 58)
    - Cricket, 1984 (Box 58)
    - Grant information and applications, 1973 (Box 58)
    - Greenfield, 1987 (Box 58)
    - Haiku, undated (Box 58)
    - Alex Haley, Roots, 1979 (Box 58)
    - End of year letters, undated (Box 58)
    - Joel Monture, 1993 (Box 58)
    - Media Center for Children, undated (Box 58)
    - New Age Journal, 1984 (Box 58)
    - New letters on the air, 1983 (Box 58)
    - Newspaper articles on Bruchac, undated; 4 (Box 58)
    - Articles and reviews, undated; 10 (Box 58)
    - Recently Completed Projects to 1996
      - A & C Black, 1990 (Box 59)
      - Anthologies, 1985-1991; 2 (Box 59)
      - Celebration Press, 1995-1996 (Box 59)
      - Centro Internatzionale, 1992 (Box 59)
      - Caffe Lena, 1995 (Box 59)
      - Callaloo issue, 1993 (Box 59)
      - Center for Multicultural Children's Literature, 1995 (Box 59)
      - Children's Television Workshop, 1991 (Box 59)
      - Clarion Books ( On the Wings of Peace, 1990 anthology), 1994-1996 (Box 59)
      - Cobblehill Books: Gluskabe and the Four Wishes, 1993-1996 (Box 59)
      - Cricket, 1998 (Box 59)
      - The Crossing Press: Tall Tales, 1996 (Box 59)
      - Crown Publishers, 1993 (Box 59)
      - Denver Museum Press, 1994 (Box 59)
      - Disney Education Productions, 1993 (Box 59)
      - Earth Trust Foundation, 1993 (Box 59)
      - Facts on File Series: Northeast Native Americans, 1989 (Box 59)
      - Fifth House, 1994-1996 (Box 59)
      - Foundation for Children's Books, 1991-1993 (Box 59)
      - Gale Research: Native American authors, 1994-1996; 3 (Box 59)
      - "Gathering the Bones", 1990 (Box 59)
      - Haurprich, Ann: Native Peoples Profile, 1993 (Box 59)
      - Harmony Books, 1986 (Box 59)
      - Holt, Rinehart: Native American Literature introduction, 1995 (Box 59)
      - Horn Book, 1995 (Box 59)
      - Holy Cow! reviews and Our Land/ Ndakinna, 1992-1996; 3 (Box 59)
      - Holt, Rinehart, and Winston, undated (Box 59)
      - Hyperion, 1991 (Box 59)
      - The Indian America Project, 1991 (Box 59)
      - In De Knipscher Publishers: The Netherlands, 1984 (Box 59)
      - INROADS, 1993 (Box 59)
      - Instructor Magazine (Scholastic), 1994 (Box 59)
      - IKO Publishers: Germany, 1982-1983 (Box 59)
      - IPS Story Earth Anthology: The Netherlands, 1992 (Box 59)
      - Indian Health Service Animals, 1995 (Box 59)
      - Intimate felationships anthology, 1995 (Box 59)
      - Knickerbocker Award, 1995 (Box 59)
      - Barbara Kouts: Literary Agency, 1993-1995 (Box 59)
      - Laughing Medusa, 1993 (Box 60)
      - Lee & Low Books, 1991-1994 (Box 60)
      - Lerner Publications, 1990-1993 (Box 60)
      - Linworth Publishing, 1993 (Box 60)
      - London, Jonathan, 1990-1993 (Box 60)
      - Lotus Press: "The Healing Earth", 1987-1990 (Box 60)
      - MacMillan, 1992-1995; 3 (Box 60)
      - Margolis Award, 1994 (Box 60)
      - UMASS Press: Native Americans of the Northeast, 1993; 2 (Box 60)
      - Joshua Morris Publishing, 1993 (Box 60)
      - Multicultural Review, 1992 (Box 60)
      - Multimedia Edizione (Italy), 1992-1993 (Box 60)
      - Monhegan Story (Melissa Fawcett), 1996 (Box 60)
      - NAPPS history book, 1994; 2 (Box 60)
      - NCTE, 1996 (Box 60)
      - National Museum of the American Indian, 1991-1994; 9 (Box 60)
      - Native American Public Broadcasting Consortium, 1996 (Box 60)
      - National Book Awards, 1995; 2 (Box 60)